Guide to the Christopher Sykes Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Christopher Sykes Papers
1809-1976
GEN MSS 612
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
17.01
(36 boxes)
The Christopher Sykes Papers document the personal and professional life of British author Christopher Sykes (1907-1986). The Papers span the dates 1909 to 1976 and contain correspondence, writings, personal papers, and photographs documenting Sykes's career as a writer as well as his work for the Foreign Office, the military, and the British Broadcasting Corporation.
Sykes, Christopher, 1907-1986
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of William S. Reese (Yale 1977), 1997.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Restricted Fragile is in cold storage and may be consulted only with permission of the appropriate curator. Preservation photocopies for reference use have been substituted in the main files.
Christopher Sykes (1907-1986)
Christopher Sykes was born on November 17, 1907 in Yorkshire, England to Mark Sykes and Edith Violet Gorst Sykes. He was educated at Downside School, Sorbonne, University of Paris (1926), and Christ Church, Oxford University (1926-1928), but left his post-secondary studies without obtaining a degree. Sykes's literary circle included Robert Byron, Evelyn Waugh, and John Betjeman, all of whom attended Oxford University during roughly the same period.
Upon leaving his studies Sykes worked for the Foreign Office as an honorary attaché at the British embassy in Berlin, Germany (1928-1929) and as a private secretary to Sir Robert Clive in Tehran, Persia (1930-1931). After a year of studies at the School of Oriental Studies in London (1933) and two years of travels through Persia and Afghanistan, Sykes returned to Tehran as secretary for the British Embassy from 1941 to 1943 and to cover the Persian-Azerbaijan Campaign for The Daily Mail in 1946.
Sykes wrote about his travels in Stranger Wonders: Tales of Travel (1937) and Innocence and Design (1935) (which he co-authored with his travel companion Robert Byron under the pseudonym Richard Waughburton). At this time, Sykes also focused on his own writing completing Wassmuss: The German Lawrence (1936) and corresponding for The Spectator and The Observer (1936-1939).
During World War II, Sykes served in the military, first with the Green Howards (1939-1941), for which he was stationed in Cairo at the Middle East Headquarters, and then for the Special Operations Executive (1943) and the Special Air Service (1943-1945). Sykes continued to write during the War and in 1944 published High Minded Murder.
Following World War II, Sykes wrote a collection of essays, Four Studies in Loyalty (1946), and served as the literary editor for the New English Review before joining the British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC) in 1948. Sykes worked for the Third Programme (1948) and then for the features department (1949-1968).
While at the BBC Sykes continued to write and his publications range from fiction, such as Answer to Question 33 (1948), Character and Situation (1949), A Song of a Shirt (1953), and Dates and Parties (1955), to non-fiction, such as Two Studies in Virtue (1953), Crossroads to Israel (1965) and Troubled Loyalty (1968). Sykes also wrote a number of biographies which include Orde Wingate (1959), Nancy: The Life of Lady Astor (1972), and Evelyn Waugh: A Biography (1975).
In 1936 Sykes married Camilla Russell (daughter of Thomas Wentworth Russell and Evelyn Dorothea Temple) with whom he had one son, Mark Sykes, in 1937. Sykes died on December 8, 1986.
Scope and Contents
The Christopher Sykes Papers document his personal and professional life and span the dates 1909 to 1976. The Papers contain correspondence, writings, personal papers, and photographs documenting Sykes's career as a writer and to a lesser extent his work with the Foreign Office, the military, and the British Broadcasting Corporation.
Sykes's correspondence provides evidence of his professional and, to a lesser degree, personal relationships. In addition to Sykes's literary agent (A.D. Peters) and publishers (Collins Publishers and Hollis and Carter), other correspondents include Isaiah Berlin, T.S. Eliot, Ivy Compton-Burnett, Philip Montefiore Magnus-Allcroft, Harold Nicolson, Cecil Roth, Rebecca Sieff, Robert Speaight, Richard Usborne, and Evelyn Waugh. Also included is correspondence with Sykes's siblings Angela Sykes Antrim, Freya Sykes Elwes, and Daniel Sykes.
Drafts, background materials, research notes, publicity materials, correspondence, and reviews document Sykes's writing career and creative process. The Papers also contain Sykes's writings while working at the BBC as well as a range of his creative output from fiction (including his children's book Albert and Emerald ) to nonfiction.
Personal papers, such as financial records, notebooks, clippings, and photographs, provide evidence of the Sykes family's personal life (including Camilla Russell Sykes's family).
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Correspondence. II. Writings. III. Personal Papers.
Authors, British -- 20th Century -- Archives; Biographers -- England; Biographers -- Great Britain; British literature -- 20th Century; Broadcasting -- Great Britain; Diplomatic and consular service, British; Radio and the arts -- Great Britain; Radio authorship; Radio scripts; Travel writers -- Great Britain; Travel writing; Great Britain -- Foreign relations -- 20th Century; Diaries; Photographs; Antrim, Angela, 1911-; Astor, David, Hon., 1912-2001; Astor, John Jacob, 1886-1971; Berlin, Isaiah, 1909-1997; Compton-Burnett, I. (Ivy), 1884-1969; Cunningham, Alan, Sir; Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns), 1888-1965; Fergusson, Bernard, 1911-1980; Fulford, Roger, 1902-1983; Haig, Douglas Haig, Earl, 1861-1928; Jacob, Ian, Sir, 1899-; Kirby, S. Woodburn (Stanley Woodburn), 1895-; Kurtz, Harold; Liddell Hart, Basil Henry, Sir, 1895-1970; Magnus, Philip, Sir (Philip Montefiore), 1906-; Nicolson, Harold, 1886-1968; Roth, Cecil, 1899-1970; Russell, Thomas Wentworth, 1879-1954; Sandford, Daniel Arthur, 1882-1972; Sieff, Rebecca, 1890-1966; Speaight, Robert, 1904-1976; Sweet-Escott, Bickham; Sykes, Christopher, 1907-1986; Waugh, Evelyn, 1903-1966; Great Britain. Army. Green Howards; Great Britain. Army. Special Air Service; A.D. Peters (Firm); British Broadcasting Corporation; British Broadcasting Corporation. Third Programme; Collins (Firm: London, England); Harper & Row, Publishers; Hodder and Stoughton; Oxford University Press
- Correspondence, 1935-1976; Series I; 2.5; (7 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains personal and professional correspondence dating from 1935 to 1976 and documents Sykes's personal relationships and career.
  - "A" General, 1953-1969, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Acton, Harold, 1966 April 26 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - A.D. Peters, 1951-1971, undated (Box 1, Folder 3-6)
  - Allen, Bill, 1955-1959, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Allen, David, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Antrim, Angela Sykes, 1939-1954, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Antrim, Randal John Somerled McDonnell, Earl of, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Astor, David, 1938-1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Astor, John Jacob, 1965-1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Astor, Michael, 1968-1970, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Astor, William, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "B" General, 1935-1969, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Includes contract between Camilla Sykes and the British and Dominions Film Corporation for her role in the film "The Belles of St. Clements"
  - Bachmann, Lawrence Paul, 1958 May 30 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Baker, Bryant, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Baldwin, John E., 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Berlin, Isaiah, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - British Air Brokers, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1953-1969, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Includes Rules of the Association of Broadcasting Staff
  - British Council, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - British Embassy, Khartoum, 1956-1959 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - British Embassy, Rangoon, 1955 November 29 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Brocklehurst, Charles, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Includes letter from Philip Brocklehurst
  - "C" General, 1939-1969, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Churchill, Winston, 1959 March (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Clarke, Dudley, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Cohen, Israel, 1953 July 8 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Collins Publishers, 1954-1971 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Includes contract for Count Van Arnim
  - Compton-Burnett, Ivy, 1954-1963 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Connell, John, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Cooke, S.A., 1958 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Cunningham, Alan, April, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - "D" General, 1953-1973, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - The Daily Mail, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Dan Leeds Productions, 1960 June/July (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - "E" General, 1955-1976 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Eliot, T.S. (Thomas Stearns), 1956, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Elwes, Freya Sykes, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Encounter, 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Evans Brothers, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - "F" General, 1952-1959 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Fergusson, Bernard, Sir, 1955-1959, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Franks, Brian, 1955-1959, undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Ford, Edward, 1966-1970 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Foreign Office, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Friends of Bar-Ilan University, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Fulford, Roger, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - "G" General, 1952-1969 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - The Geographical Magazine, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Gray, B.H. (Brian H.), 1952 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - "H" General, 1939-1970 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Haig, Douglas, Sir, 1937, undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - The Harold Watson Company, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Harper and Row, Publishers, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Harrison, Rosemary, 1971 August (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Hart, B. H. Liddell (Basil Henry Liddell), Sir, 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Head, Antony, 1939-1958 undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Hever, Lord Astor of, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Hillier, Stella, 1952-1954 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Hodder and Stoughton, 1959 August - September (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Hollis and Carter, 1953-1960 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - "I" General, 1956-1969, undated (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Imperial War Museum (Great Britain), 1959 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Ironside, William Edmund, 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Israel. Embassy (United Kingdom), 1954-1959 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - "J" General, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Jacob, Ian, Sir, 1959 June-July (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Jelley, Enid, 1956-1959, undated (Box 3, Folder 70)
    Includes three photographs of Orde Wingate (one of which is a group shot with unidentified people)
  - Jones, Margaret, 1966-1969 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - "K" General, 1952-1970 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Kelly, Denis, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Kirby, S. Woodburn (Stanley Woodburn), 1957-1959 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Kurtz, Harold, 1952-1963, undated (Box 3, Folder 75)
    Includes information about auditions for "The Trial of Marshal Ney"
  - "L" General, 1937-1969, undated (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Lancaster, Nancy, 1969, undated (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Langhorne, Betty, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - The Library, House of Commons. England., 1969 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - "M" General, 1952-1970, undated (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Magnus-Allcroft, Philip, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - McLean, Neil, 1957 November 15 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    Includes McLean's war diary
  - Musters, Judy, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - "N" General, 1951-1963 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - National Library of Wales, 1971 May 7 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Nicolson, Harold, 1959 April (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - "O" General, 1942-1959, undated (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - The Observer, 1955-1971, undated (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Office of the High Commissioner for the United Kingdom - New Delhi, 1955-1959 (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - Oxford University Press, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - "P" General, 1952-1970 (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Philip, Aiden, undated (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - Pollen, Daphne, 1970 March-April (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Prime Minister's Office. England., 1959 April 9 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Queen's College, (University of Oxford), 1970 July (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - "R" General, 1952-1963, undated (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - Roth, Cecil, 1953-1955 (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - Rotol Limited, 1957 March 15 (Box 4, Folder 98)
  - Rooke-Ley, Basil, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - Royal Geographical Society (Great Britain), 1958 (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - Russell, John, 1940-1942, undated (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - "S" General, 1952-1973, undated (Box 4, Folder 102)
    Letter from James Smith includes photograph of his battalion while in Addis Ababa
  - Sackville-West, Edward, Hon., 1959 May 19 (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - Sandford, Daniel Arthur, 1955-1959 (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - Sewell, Dolly, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 105)
    Includes article "Cables Under the Atlantic"
  - Sieff, Rebecca, 1938-1959 (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - Smith, Lorna, 1954-1958, undated (Box 5, Folder 107)
  - Smith, Simon Nowell, 1960-1961 (Box 5, Folder 108)
  - Speaight, Robert, 1955-1970 (Box 5, Folder 109)
  - Stone, Janet, 1970-1973, undated (Box 5, Folder 110)
  - The Sunday Times, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 111)
  - Sweet-Escott, Bickham, 1959-1973 (Box 5, Folder 112)
  - Sykes, Camilla, undated (Box 5, Folder 113)
  - Sykes, Christopher, outgoing, 1955-1970, undated (Box 5, Folder 114)
  - Sykes, Daniel, 1940-1954 (Box 5, Folder 115)
  - "T" General, 1952-1969 (Box 5, Folder 116)
  - Taylor, Peter E., 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 117)
  - Thompson, Bob, 1955, undated (Box 5, Folder 118)
  - Time and Tide, 1955-1960 (Box 5, Folder 119)
  - T.R. Fyvel, European Publishers, 1955-1959 (Box 5, Folder 120)
  - Tree, Mary Endicott (Marietta), undated (Box 5, Folder 121)
  - Tulloch, Derek, 1955-1959 (Box 5, Folder 122)
  - Tweedsmuir, Susan, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 123)
  - University of Liverpool, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 124)
  - Usborne, Richard, 1956 June, undated (Box 5, Folder 125)
  - "V" General, 1956-1971, undated (Box 5, Folder 126)
  - Vyvyan, J. M. K., 1954, undated (Box 5, Folder 127)
  - "W" General, 1952-1969, undated (Box 5, Folder 128)
  - Waugh, Evelyn, 1962, undated (Box 5, Folder 129)
  - Waugh, Laura, undated (Box 5, Folder 130)
  - Weizman House, 1942-1959 (Box 5, Folder 131)
  - West, Anderson and Co., 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 132)
  - Wingate, Granville, 1955-1963, undated (Box 5, Folder 133)
    Includes photograph of Orde Wingate's grave
  - Wingate, Iris, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 134)
  - Wingate, Monica, 1958 June (Box 5, Folder 135)
  - Wingate, Nigel, 1955-1958 (Box 5, Folder 136)
  - Wingate, Ronald, 1957-1960 (Box 5, Folder 137)
  - Wingate, Sybil, 1955-1959 (Box 5, Folder 138)
  - Winn, Alice, 1970, undated (Box 6, Folder 139)
  - World Publishing Company, 1959, undated (Box 6, Folder 140)
  - "Z" General, 1953-1959,undated (Box 6, Folder 141)
  - Christmas cards, 1956-1970 (Box 6, Folder 142-149)
  - Christmas cards, 1956-1970 (Box 7, Folder 150-155)
  - Unidentified, 1952-1969 (Box 7, Folder 156-163)
- Writings, 1936-1976; Series II; 8.55; (21 boxes)
  The series is organized into six subseries: Major Works, Articles, Playscripts, Radio Scripts, Other Writings and Writings of Others. Sykes's writings are arranged alphabetically by title and Writings of Others is arranged alphabetically by author (when known).
  The series contains drafts, background materials, research notes, publicity materials, correspondence, and reviews documenting Sykes's writing career between 1936 and 1976.
  - Major Works
    - Albert and Emerald
      - Draft, holograph, corrected and illustrated, 1961, undated (Box 8, Folder 164)
    - Crossroads to Israel
      - Maps of Israel, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 165)
      - Clippings on Israel and other background material, 1953-1963 (Box 8, Folder 166)
      - Notebook, Before 1965 (Box 8, Folder 167)
      - Research notes, Before 1965 (Box 8, Folder 168-170)
      - Draft, holograph, corrected, Before 1965 (Box 9, Folder 171-177)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, Before 1965 (Box 10, Folder 178-183)
      - Reviews, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 184)
    - The Damascus Road
      - Draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 10, Folder 185)
    - Dates and Parties
      - Draft, holograph, corrected, Before 1955 (Box 11, Folder 186-188)
    - Evelyn Waugh: A Biography
      - Background material, undated (Box 11, Folder 189)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, Before 1975 (Box 12, Folder 190-194)
      - Reviews, 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 195-197)
    - Nancy: The Life of Lady Astor
      - Background material and research notes, Before 1972 (Box 13, Folder 198-202)
        Contains photocopies of letters to Lady Astor from George Bernard Shaw between 1928 and 1950.
      - Draft, holograph, corrected, Before 1972 (Box 14, Folder 203-208)
      - Draft, holograph, corrected, Before 1972 (Box 15, Folder 209-212)
      - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, Before 1972 (Box 15, Folder 213-214)
      - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, Before 1972 (Box 16, Folder 215-216)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, Before 1972 (Box 16, Folder 217-222)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, Before 1972 (Box 17, Folder 223-224)
      - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, circa 1972 (Box 17, Folder 225-228)
      - Draft fragments, typescript, corrected, Before 1972 (Box 18, Folder 229-230)
      - Galley proofs, corrected, circa 1972
    - Orde Wingate
      - Gideon Goes to War by Leonard Mosley, annotated, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 231)
      - Maps of India, Pakistan, Ceylon, Burma, Malaya, Indo-China, Eritrea, Somalia, and Ethiopia, 1953-1955 (Box 18, Folder 232-233)
      - Garrison Map of Anglo-Egyptian Sudan, 1931
      - Research notes, Before 1959 (Box 18, Folder 234-235)
      - Research notes, Before 1959 (Box 19, Folder 236-241)
      - Draft, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, Before 1959 (Box 20, Folder 242-248)
      - Draft, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, Before 1959 (Box 21, Folder 249-258)
      - Draft, typescript carbon, Before 1959 (Box 22, Folder 259-265)
      - Draft fragments, typescript, corrected, Before 1959 (Box 22, Folder 266-267)
      - Notes regarding edits and other comments of drafts, Before 1959 (Box 23, Folder 268-269)
      - Publishing contract, typescript, carbon, 1959 March 24 (Box 23, Folder 270)
      - Publicity material, circa 1959 (Box 23, Folder 271)
      - Reviews, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 272-274)
      - Dramatic adaptation "Orde Wingate: Three 50' Plays" by Don Shaw for the BBC, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 275-279)
    - Troubled Loyalty
      - Publishing contract for German translation, 1969 April 4 (Box 23, Folder 280)
      - Review, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 281)
    - Wassmuss: The German Lawrence
      - Reviews, 1936 (Box 23, Folder 282)
  - Articles
    - "Birthday of the Third", published version, undated (Box 24, Folder 283)
    - "Colonel Sibthorp: A Festival Centenary", printed version, undated (Box 24, Folder 284)
    - "Ghost Autobiography", draft, typescript, corrected and printed version, undated (Box 24, Folder 285)
    - "A Literary Stumbling Block", draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 24, Folder 286)
    - "More Windsor Memoirs", draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 24, Folder 287)
    - "The Mystery Parcel", draft, typescript carbon, corrected and published version, 1955 June 30, undated (Box 24, Folder 288)
    - "Nancy Lancaster", draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 24, Folder 289)
    - "The Old School Tie and Others", draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 24, Folder 290)
    - "A People of Poetry, Not Prose", printed version, 1959 May 5
    - "Persecution", draft, typescript, undated (Box 24, Folder 291)
    - "Remembering the Duke", printed version, 1952 September 12
    - "Sir Max Beerbohm", draft, typescript, undated (Box 24, Folder 292)
    - Draft fragments, undated (Box 24, Folder 293-294)
    - Background material, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 295)
  - Playscripts
    - "Gilbert Pinfold", draft, typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 24, Folder 296)
    - "One Man Must Die"
      - Background notes, undated (Box 24, Folder 297)
      - Draft, typescript, incomplete, undated (Box 24, Folder 298)
    - "Sophokles Traxiniai", typescript, undated (Box 24, Folder 299)
      Produced by Sykes
    - "The Valldemosa Affair", draft, typescript, annotated, undated (Box 24, Folder 300)
  - Radio Scripts
    - Drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1953-1964, undated (Box 25, Folder 301-306)
    - Publicity and reviews, 1948-1952 (Box 25, Folder 307)
  - Other Writings
    - "A Talk on Biography", draft, typescript, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 308)
      Delivered to the Eton College Library Society
    - Book reviews, drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected and printed versions, 1951-1966, undated (Box 26, Folder 309-312)
    - Letters to the editor, 1939-1956 (Box 26, Folder 313)
    - Notebook on Ernst Herzfeld's A Journey Through Luristan, Arabistan and Fars, holograph, undated (Box 26, Folder 314)
    - Unidentified notebooks, undated (Box 26, Folder 315-318)
    - Unidentified notebooks, undated (Box 27, Folder 319-320)
  - Writings of Others
    - Gattie, Kenneth, "All Change", typescript, 1953 (Box 27, Folder 321)
    - Margheritta, B.C., "A Book of Verse", 1956 (Box 27, Folder 322)
    - Russell, Dorothea, "The Zar" and "Easter in the Holy City", draft, typescript, undated (Box 27, Folder 323)
    - Russell, Dorothea, untitled autobiography, draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 27, Folder 324)
    - Maulnier, Thierry, "Le Profanateur", typescript, corrected, After 1950 (Box 27, Folder 325)
    - Sykes, Camilla, translator, "Diary of a Diplomat", draft, typescript carbon, undated (Box 28, Folder 326-328)
    - Unidentified, The Chindit, 1956 June (Box 28, Folder 329)
    - Unidentified, "Missing Parachutists", After 1945 (Box 28, Folder 330)
- Personal Papers and Photographs, 1909-1971; Series III; 2.29; (6 boxes)
  The series is organized into three subseries: Financial Records, Other Papers, and Photographs.
  The series contains personal papers, such as financial records, notebooks, clippings, and photographs, which document the Sykes family between 1909 and 1971. The series also contains material documenting Camilla Russell Sykes's family.
  - Financial and Legal Records
    - Insurance, 1941-1971 (Box 29, Folder 331-336)
    - Royalties and bills, 1938-1945, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 337)
  - Other Papers
    - Class notes, undated (Box 30, Folder 338-340)
    - Sketchbooks, undated (Box 30, Folder 341-342)
    - "East Africa Force Campaign: Supplementary Report", 1941
    - List of plants at Sykes's home Shute House, undated (Box 30, Folder 343)
    - Clippings of articles about the Sykes family, 1935-1957 (Box 30, Folder 344-346)
    - Brochures and invitations, 1955-1976 (Box 30, Folder 347)
    - Material relating to Thomas Wentworth Russell, 1914, 1954, undated (Box 30, Folder 348-349)
      Includes interview with Camilla Sykes, silhouettes of Russell family members, and material relating to Russell's funeral such as programs and a sketch for a memorial monument
    - Musical scores including manuscript of Norman Kay's "The Sailor's Wife" and printed version of Ronald Jamieson's "In a Golden Coach", 1952, undated (Box 30, Folder 350)
    - Advertisement from Basilisk Press for reprint of The Kelmscott Chaucer, undated
  - Photographs
    - Camilla Sykes as child and Russell family, 1909-1912, undated (Box 31, Folder 351-354)
    - Camilla Sykes as young woman and Sykes wedding, circa 1936 (Box 31, Folder 355)
    - Sykes family and friends at Donhead Hall and Radbrock, undated (Box 31, Folder 356-363)
    - Sykes family and friends, circa 1930s - 1972, undated (Box 31, Folder 364-371)